<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weasis Medical Viewer on Weasis Documentation</title>
    <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weasis Medical Viewer on Weasis Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nroduit.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding in dcm4chee</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/getting-started/dcm4chee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/getting-started/dcm4chee/</guid>
      <description>This page describes how installing Weasis to be the default web viewer of dcm4chee web interface. See How to launch Weasis from any environments to integrate Weasis into your own user interface.
Weasis is launched from the dcm4chee administrative web interface with the weasis protocol, as shown in the pictures below. The documentation where Weasis is launched with Java Webstart is still available here. 
For dcm4chee-arc-light  Install dcm4chee, if not already done (Installation with Docker is straightforward).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding in dcm4chee (deprecated)</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/old/dcm4chee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/old/dcm4chee/</guid>
      <description>This page describes how installing Weasis to be the default web viewer of dcm4chee web interface.
Weasis is launched from the dcm4chee administrative web interface with Java Webstart, as shown in the pictures below. It may also be copied to a CD (or other removable devices) with images.
Use the [weasis protocol](../../getting-started/weasis-protocol) instead of Java Web Start because it has been removed from Java 11 release and because the end of public Oracle Java 8 updates from April 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/integration/</guid>
      <description>How to launch Weasis from any environments Here we present how to launch Weasis with associated images from any context either using weasis-pacs-connector or by building its own connector. The launch of the application is based on the weasis protocol available since version 3.5. However, it is still possible to use weasis 3.5 with Java Webstart (but only with Java 8 to 10), see the old documentation.
The easiest way to launch Weasis from a web context is to use weasis-pacs-connector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weasis Architecture</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/architecture/</guid>
      <description>Weasis has a modular architecture based on OSGi: the dynamic module system for Java. It uses the Apache Felix OSGi framework which is an open source implementation of the OSGi Release 4.2 specification (OSGi Certified).
The following schemas show the main different plug-in types (bundle in OSGi language) and their relationships. Viewer, Viewer Tool Pane, Tool Bar, Data Explorer and Codec bundles are registered dynamically by the Declarative Services (a way to push or to consume services in OSGi environment).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration (deprecated)</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/old/integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/old/integration/</guid>
      <description>How to launch Weasis from any environments There are two Weasis distributions: the WEB distribution (weasis.war) and the portable distribution (weasis-portable.zip). Here we are presenting how to connect the WEB distribution with any web application. This documentation is adapted for Weasis 2.5 and superior working with Java Webstart. The easiest way to launch Weasis from a web context is to use weasis-pacs-connector.
Use the [weasis protocol](../../getting-started/weasis-protocol) instead of Java Web Start because it has been removed from Java 11 release and because the end of public Oracle Java 8 updates from April 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weasis Web Protocol</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/getting-started/weasis-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/getting-started/weasis-protocol/</guid>
      <description>The web protocol allows to launch Weasis in a web context from a specific URI scheme: weasis://parameters
Requires Weasis 3.5 (or superior) installed on the system with a [native installer](../).  How to use the weasis protocol  From a web page, just make a link starting with weasis:// (see below How to build an URI) Some web frameworks such as the wiki or the URL field of some browsers only support the standard protocols (http, ftp&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preferences</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/preferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/preferences/</guid>
      <description>The WEB distribution (weasis.war) allows to deliver preferences from the server side to the client side. Some preferences on the server side are used by Weasis only during the first launch, because they can be changed lately in the Weasis user interface. The other preferences at server side are used by Weasis at every launch.
Local preferences can be modified:
 in the Weasis user interface: File &amp;gt; Preferences in files stored in ${user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Keyboard and Mouse Shortcuts  IHE recommendations in Basic Image Review profile.
Selected view of the 2D DICOM Viewer    Shortcut Action     T Translate (pan) the image canvas    W Window / Level    S Series scroll    Z Zoom    R Rotation   H Crosshair: in multiview mode synchronizes the crosshair position to all the views (Note: Ctrl + click or Ctrl + Shift + click allows changing the Window / Level values)   C Cine Start / Stop   M Measure   D Distance measurement    A Angle measurement    Y Polyline measurement   B Textbox   Q Context menu   Ctrl + Spacebar Change to the next action   Ctrl + mouse drag Accelerate the current action    Ctrl + Shift + mouse drag Accelerate more the current action   Alt + R 90° rotation (clockwise)   Alt + L 90° rotation (counterclockwise)   Alt + F Flip horizontally (after rotation action)   0 1 2 3&amp;hellip; DICOM presets   K Toggle key image state   Spacebar Show/Hide all the annotations (three states)   I Show/Hide all the annotations (three states)    Escape Reset the selected view    P Print view(s) with the operating system printer    Right-click Open the contextual menu for more options   Double click Toggle fullscreen   Drag files/directories</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoom</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/zoom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/zoom/</guid>
      <description>Zoom tool The zoom tool can be associated with one of three mouse buttons or with the mouse scroll (top left toolbar). In the image below the zoom tool is associated with the left mouse button.
The zoom factor can be modified from different locations:
 by dragging the cursor over the image with the configured mouse button by scrolling the mouse wheel when configured by selecting an item in the zoom dropdown button in the toolbar from the context menu: right-click on the image &amp;gt; Zoom form the slider in the image tool panel  The zoom function always zooms in/out to the center of the screen regardless of where the cursor is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Plug-ins</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/build-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/build-plugins/</guid>
      <description>How to build and install a plug-in This page describes how to build new Weasis plug-ins and how they can be incorporated into the distributions, see also this page for the IDE configuration.
List of plug-ins types  Media viewer or editor (main central panel that implements ViewerPlugin or ImageViewerPlugin and the factory implements SeriesViewerFactory) Toolbar associated with a viewer (implements Toolbar) Tool associated with a viewer (right panel that implements DockableTool) Data Explorer (data model implements DataExplorerModel and data view implements DataExplorerView, and the factory implements DataExplorerViewFactory) Import data into an explorer (ex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Weasis</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/getting-started/building-weasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/getting-started/building-weasis/</guid>
      <description>These instructions describe how to build Weasis directly from the Git repository on any platform. For building Weasis from an IDE, see Weasis plug-in development guidelines.
Prerequisites
 JDK 11 or higher Maven 3.5 or higher
If your computer is behind a proxy server, configure maven. Git or directly download source from github  Getting the Source To clone the repository, first install GIT and either clone using a graphical GIT client or directly from the command line using the command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/getting-started/guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/getting-started/guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Weasis Plug-in Development This page is intended for developers who want to contribute to Weasis and it is a recommendation for developers who want to create their own plug-ins, see also How to build and install a plug-in.
We recommend the use of Eclipse IDE, because all the following instructions are based on it and some settings and the coding conventions can be imported directly into Eclipse. Nevertheless, for having a better Maven integration, it is possible to use IntelliJ IDEA or Netbeans by configuring weasis-launcher with similar instructions described in Debug or Run from Eclipse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weasis Commands</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/commands/</guid>
      <description>The commands listed below can be applied at start-up or in a telnet session. All the commands starting with &amp;ldquo;dcmview2d:&amp;rdquo; allow to drive Weasis and are not adapted to be used at start-up.
This page matches to Weasis 2.5.1 or higher. The syntax of usage comes from POSIX.  To obtain the list of commands, after starting Weasis, open a local telnet session of the OSGI Console and type lb for getting the list of bundles and their state or type help for getting all the available commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dicom Conformance</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/dicom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/dicom/</guid>
      <description>Compatibility of DICOM Transfer Syntax    Transfer Syntax UID Description Supported     1.2.840.10008.1.2 Implicit VR - Little Endian yes   1.2.840.10008.1.2.1 Explicit VR - Little Endian yes   1.2.840.10008.1.2.2 Explicit VR - Big Endian yes   1.2.840.10008.1.2.5 RLE (Run Length Encoding) Lossless yes   1.2.840.10008.1.2.4.50 JPEG Baseline (Process 1): Default Transfer Syntax for Lossy JPEG 8 Bit Image Compression yes   1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebuild dcm4chee-web</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/old/rebuild-dcm4chee-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/old/rebuild-dcm4chee-web/</guid>
      <description>Build dcm4chee-web 2.15.0, 2.16.2 or 2.17.0 Prerequisites  Subversion (SVN), one of the following client:  Subversion - The core system (server, client, libs) Subversive - SVN Team Client (Eclipse plugin) TortoiseSVN - Handy SVN client for Windows systems  JDK 6 or higher Ant 1.6 or higher  Getting the Source To check out the code, first install Subversion and either checkout the trunk branch using a graphical Subversion client (such as TortoiseSVN) or directly from the command line using the command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internationalization</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/getting-started/translating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/getting-started/translating/</guid>
      <description>The translation files are now hosted and managed on Transifex website. Get an account at Transifex and help to translate to your language! If your language is missing, just head over to Transifex and request a new language.
**Text length**: The translations for many languages frequently exceed the length of the corresponding English source. It could be a problem for the layout of graphical components (e.g. buttons).  **Special characters**: Some characters representing values (%d, %s), newline (\\n) and HTML tags must not be translated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DICOM Attributes</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/tags/</guid>
      <description>How to display DICOM attributes The DICOM attributes can be displayed either by:
 selecting the &amp;ldquo;Dicom Information&amp;rdquo; layout from the layout dropdown button (A) clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Dicom Information&amp;rdquo; button in the toolbar to open a detached window (B)  Using the view in the layout (A) allows updating dynamically the DICOM attributes to the current image (e.g. scrolling into the series). The DICOM attributes won&#39;t change when opening the detached window (B).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histogram</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/histo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/histo/</guid>
      <description>Displaying Histogram Displaying the histogram allows you to view the distribution of the modality values.
Displaying the histogram allow to better understand the effect on the pixel distribution wen changing all the LUT parameters from the Image Tool right panel.  To open the histogram, select the &amp;ldquo;Histogram&amp;rdquo; layout from the Layouts dropdown button (see the image below).
General histogram parameters:
 Channel: With gray images only the Luminance channel is available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Print</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/print/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/print/</guid>
      <description>Build the image selection to print The image selection to print must be prepared before calling the print function. If you need to print more than one image per page, choose a layout from the dropdown button in the toolbar (1).
The layout list is built dynamically according to the window size. So changing the window size ratio will provide other layouts. For instance, with a panoramic screen, you can choose a horizontal layout and then print with a landscape orientation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build KO and PR</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/build-ko-pr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/build-ko-pr/</guid>
      <description>How to build and export DICOM KO and PR Key Object Selection (KO)  To display KO Toolbar, select in menu: View &amp;gt; Toolbars &amp;gt; Key Object Selection Toolbar Click on the right icon over the image to select the Key Object Selection. Click on the star icon (or press &amp;lsquo;k&amp;rsquo;) to create in a new KO or to add the key image.
  Presentation State (PR or GSPS)  Open PR: Since Weasis 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy server</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/proxy/</guid>
      <description>How to configure a proxy server Manual configuration from the user interface From the main menu, open File &amp;gt; Preferences (Alt + P) and select Proxy Server.
The default configuration is Direct connection (no proxy) and by clicking on Manual proxy configuration you can define a custom proxy server (in the image below, a local proxy like Squid).
To fill in the fields you must refer to the Java documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Calibration</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/calibration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/calibration/</guid>
      <description> How to change the spatial calibration   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/locale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/locale/</guid>
      <description>How to change the language and regional settings Switching from the user interface From the main menu, open File &amp;gt; Preferences (Alt + P) and select the desired language and the regional format. The languages available in the list can be partially translated, check Internationalization.
Anywhere in the user interface, date and number should be displayed with the selected regional format.  Changing the default locale settings If you need to change the default settings, please see the preferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styles and themes</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/tutorials/theme/</guid>
      <description>How to apply another theme Changing from the user interface From the main menu, open File &amp;gt; Preferences (Alt + P) and select the desired look and feel (click on &amp;ldquo;show&amp;rdquo; to see a partial preview)
Changing the default look and feel value See preferences</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weasis Multi-Touch</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/stories/touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/stories/touch/</guid>
      <description>Master Thesis of Gérôme Pasquier   Try it from the demo server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQs</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/faq/</guid>
      <description>Frequently Asked Questions 
 
 Why is the Weasis license Eclipse Public License? &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;  
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;expand-content&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;display: none;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;  The Eclipse Public License is an OSI approved license and a commercially friendly copyleft license.
EPL is more business-friendly about some patent retaliation and reverse engineering clauses than LGPL. With EPL, derivative work (weasis plugin) can be distributed in any license type: open source, freeware, commercial&amp;hellip; However, if you distribute Weasis with some modifications (changing existing source code of the open source Weasis plug-ins), even if it is a free distribution, you are obligated to make your modifications available to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Involved!</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/get-involved/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/get-involved/</guid>
      <description>Report Bugs and Enhancements First, look at the GitHub issues system, the forum and/or this website (like FAQs or Getting Started) to see if your problem has not been reported yet.
Only then, fill a bug on GitHub with the most details from a template.
Become a Committer  Become a committer on an existing project or on one of the incubating projects, for Weasis use pull requests.  Share Your Knowledge  Do you or your company have a success story about Weasis?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Weasis</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/demo/</guid>
      <description>Demo with multiple DICOM Samples This page shows a list of DICOM samples for testing viewer capabilities.
**Naming convention** - Patient name starting with &#34;TEST^&#34; and then the general test purpose. &#34;TEST-i18n-&#34; prefix is for internationalization test. - In study description: general test description - In series description: test description  The demo server is on a free cloud system, so sometimes it requires to launch two times the viewer because the server has to wake up (is turned &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>