<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Customize on Weasis Documentation</title>
    <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Customize on Weasis Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/integration/</guid>
      <description>How to launch Weasis from any environments Here we present how to launch Weasis with associated images from any context either using weasis-pacs-connector or by building your own connector. The launch of the application is based on the weasis protocol available since version 3.5. However, it is still possible to use weasis 3.5 with Java Webstart (but only with Java 8 to 10), see the old documentation.
Using weasis-pacs-connector allows a high degree of integration and facilitates connection to a PACS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preferences</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/preferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/preferences/</guid>
      <description>The WEB distribution (weasis.war) allows to deliver preferences from the server side to the client side. Some preferences on the server side are used by Weasis only during the first launch, because they can be changed lately in the Weasis user interface. The other preferences at server side are used by Weasis at every launch.
Local preferences can be modified:
 in the Weasis user interface: File &amp;gt; Preferences in files stored in ${user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Plug-ins</title>
      <link>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/build-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nroduit.github.io/en/basics/customize/build-plugins/</guid>
      <description>How to build and install a plug-in This page describes how to build new Weasis plug-ins and how they can be incorporated into the distributions, see also this page for the IDE configuration.
List of plug-ins types  Media viewer or editor (main central panel that implements ViewerPlugin or ImageViewerPlugin and the factory implements SeriesViewerFactory) Toolbar associated with a viewer (implements Toolbar) Tool associated with a viewer (right panel that implements DockableTool) Data Explorer (data model implements DataExplorerModel and data view implements DataExplorerView, and the factory implements DataExplorerViewFactory) Import data into an explorer (ex.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>